<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSTI on Satish&#39;s Scribbles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ssti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSTI on Satish&#39;s Scribbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Satish Patra</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ssti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Detection to Flag: Python Jinja2 SSTI on Root-Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/rootme-jinja2-ssti-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/rootme-jinja2-ssti-walkthrough/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently tackled a fun Server-side Template Injection (SSTI) challenge on Root-Me and wanted to document my process. This post follows my journey from initial detection to crafting a reliable, context-free payload to gain code execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge-python-ssti-introduction&#34;&gt;The Challenge: Python SSTI Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was to solve the &amp;ldquo;Python - Server-side Template Injection Introduction&amp;rdquo; challenge on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.root-me.org/en/Challenges/Web-Server/Python-Server-side-Template-Injection-Introduction?lang=en&#34;&gt;Root-me.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-setup-&#34;&gt;&amp;laquo; SETUP &amp;raquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by loading the challenge environment and intercepting the requests using Caido. The application allows you to preview content submitted through a form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepening My SSTI Knowledge: Java SSTI on Root-Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ssti-study-and-rootme-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ssti-study-and-rootme-challenge/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my first taste of Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) with the PicoCTF challenge, I was hooked. It was a relatively straightforward introduction, and it left me wanting to learn more. This post documents my journey of diving deeper into SSTI, from studying the theory to solving a more complex challenge on Root-Me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broadening-my-ssti-understanding&#34;&gt;Broadening My SSTI Understanding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by consuming as much information as I could find on SSTI. Here are some of the resources I found most helpful:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First SSTI Adventure: A PicoCTF Walkthrough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/picoctf-ssti-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/picoctf-ssti-journey/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently dove into the world of Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI) and it was a blast! I decided to tackle a PicoCTF challenge to test my skills, and it turned out to be a fantastic learning experience. Here’s a breakdown of my journey from finding the vulnerability to getting the flag, as it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-ssti&#34;&gt;What is SSTI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSTI, or Server-Side Template Injection, is a vulnerability that occurs when an attacker can inject malicious code into a template, which is then executed on the server. This can lead to serious consequences, including Remote Code Execution (RCE), allowing the attacker to run arbitrary commands on the server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
